Today's Puja of Vishnumaya,
Bugünün Vishnumaya Pujaları,
who was the sister of Shri Krishna,
Shri Krishna'nın kız kardeşi kimdi?
was not scheduled as such in an international
uluslararası bir şekilde planlanmadı
pujas that we do.
Yaptığımız pijamalar.
But they say for the love of God
Ama derler ki Tanrı aşkına
when all the devotees assemble,
Bütün adanmışlar toplandığında,
God also has to break many rules,
Tanrı ayrıca birçok kuralı çiğnemek zorundadır.
and that's how this puja has been accepted to be done.
ve bu pujanın yapılması kabul edildi.
At least once it should be done, I think, was a good idea.
En azından bir kere yapılması gerekiyor, bence, iyi bir fikirdi.
By your love
Aşkınla
and your devotion it was desired,
ve adanmışlığınız istenen,
and so this puja is going to be performed.
ve böylece bu puja gerçekleştirilecek.
It's just spontaneous
Sadece kendiliğinden
that I happened to be in England at this time,
şu anda İngiltere'de olduğumu,
because this puja if ever had happened,
Çünkü bu puja hiç olsaydı,
would have happened in India.
Hindistan'da olacaktı.
Because this is a puja of a deity,
Çünkü bu bir tanrının pujası.
Vishnumaya,
Vishnumaya,
the seed of which is not easy to plant
tohum ekimi kolay değildir
in the Western countries.
Batı ülkelerinde.
Now the whole shakti programming has been done
Şimdi bütün shakti programlama yapıldı
in such a way that we have Mother as a Shakti first,
Öyle ki, önce bir Shakti olarak annem olacak.
the Primordial Mother.
İlkel Anne.
Then we have three shaktis coming out of Her,
O zaman Ondan çıkan üç shaktimiz var.
as you know - Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati.
bildiğiniz gibi - Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati.
And then we have children from them:
Sonra onlardan çocuklarımız var:
brothers and sisters.
erkekkardeşler ve kızkardeşler.
So before the power
Yani güçten önce
of what we call the wife or the spouse was created,
karısı ya da eşi dediğimiz şeyin yaratıldığı,
is the power of the sister is created.
Kız kardeşin gücü yaratılır.
So, as you know that Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha were born
Bildiğiniz gibi Brahma, Vishnu ve Mahesha doğdu.
to these three Shaktis,
bu üç Shaktis’e,
and they all had sisters.
ve hepsinin kızkardeşi vardı.
And their sisters were married
Ve kız kardeşleri evli
- like Vishnu's sister is Parvati
- Vishnu'nun kız kardeşi Parvati gibi
and She was married to Shiva.
ve Shiva ile evlendi.
Is very important to understand
Anlamak çok önemli
that these three types of powers
bu üç tür güç
always play on the chakras.
her zaman çakralarda oynarlar.
And if you understand these three powers,
Ve eğer bu üç gücü anlarsanız,
how they play,
nasıl oynuyorlar
then you will understand
o zaman anlayacaksın
what is the importance of Vishnumaya is.
Vishnumaya'nın önemi nedir.
Vishnumaya is the power of a sister in a family.
Vishnumaya, bir ailedeki kız kardeşin gücüdür.
So the female is the power,
Yani kadın güçtür,
and the male is the kinetic power
ve erkek kinetik güçtür
which asserts the powers
hangi güçleri iddia eder
of these three powers which surround him.
onu çevreleyen bu üç güçten.
So when the male power comes in,
Yani erkek gücü geldiğinde,
all these powers become
tüm bu güçler olur
helpful acting associates with that power.
yardımcı oyunculuk bu güç ile ilişkilendirir.
Now Vishnumaya's power is very important to understand,
Şimdi Vishnumaya'nın gücünü anlamak çok önemli.
because Mother power is to protect your innocence,
Çünkü ana güç senin masumiyetini korumaktır.
because that is the most important thing.
çünkü bu en önemli şey.
To protect your innocence is the Mother's power.
Masumiyetini korumak, Annenin gücüdür.
Now, Vishnumaya's power is to protect your chastity.
Şimdi, Vishnumaya'nın gücü iffetinizi korumaktır.
You don't understand sometimes what is chastity
Anlamıyorsun bazen iffet nedir
and what is innocence.
ve masumiyet nedir.
Innocence is a power which is not acted upon.
Masumiyet, harekete geçmeyen bir güçtür.
Like we have electricity in our house,
Evimizde elektrik varmış gibi,
the electricity exists like innocence exists within us;
elektrik, içimizde var olan masumiyet gibi var olur;
but enactment of that is done through chastity.
ancak bunun yürürlüğe girmesi iffetle yapılır.
A person can say,
Bir kişi söyleyebilir
"I did this very innocently" - no, he cannot.
“Bunu çok masumca yaptım” - hayır, yapamaz.
Because whatever you do if it is innocent,
Çünkü masumsa ne yaparsan yap,
cannot be harmful to your character,
karakterine zararlı olamaz,
to your innocence or to your righteousness.
masumiyetine veya doğruluğuna.
So those people who say like this,
Yani böyle söyleyenler,
that "I did it innocently" are wrong,
"Ben masumca yaptım" yanlış,
because innocently if you do anything it becomes chastity.
çünkü masum bir şey yaparsanız iffet olur.
So when innocence is practiced it becomes chastity.
Böylece masumiyet uygulandığında iffet olur.
You must have respect of your chastity.
İffetine saygı duymalısın.
Chastity is the one which is Vishnumaya's power within us,
İffet, Vishnumaya'nın içimizdeki gücüdür.
Gauri's power, is the pure virgin.
Gauri'nin gücü, saf bakiredir.
She doesn't marry.
O evlenmiyor.
As you know that Vishnumaya was created,
Bildiğiniz gibi Vishnumaya'nın yaratıldığını,
just after Her birth She was killed by Kamsa.
Doğduktan hemen sonra Kamsa tarafından öldürüldü.
Now to understand the significance of chastity within us,
Şimdi, içimizdeki iffetin önemini anlamak için,
we have to know that chastity is the foundation
iffetin temel olduğunu bilmek zorundayız
of all dharmas.
Tüm dharmalar
Unless and until you have sense of chastity
Sürece ve iffet duygusu olana kadar
you cannot have dharma.
Dharma'ya sahip olamazsınız.
Dharma is not possible because that's the foundation.
Dharma mümkün değil çünkü temel bu.
It will be a house of cards;
Bir kart evi olacak;
if you do not have the foundation of chastity
iffet temeli yoksa
it will just collapse in no time.
sadece kısa sürede çökecek.
So is a very important thing is chastity
Yani çok önemli bir şey iffet
which has been challenged in the West throughout,
Batı'da meydan okudu,
and that's why I'm saying is difficult
ve bu yüzden zor diyorum
to sow the seed of chastity in this country.
Bu ülkede iffet tohumunu ekmek.
And that it should happen,
Ve olması gerektiği
there must be some divine plan I think,
Sanırım ilahi bir plan olmalı.
that it has happened that this great puja
oldu ki bu büyük puja
should be performed here.
burada yapılmalıdır.
It's not a easy puja to do
Yapması kolay bir puja değil.
- is to be done by people who are innocent,
- masum insanlar tarafından yapılacaktır,
done by people who have lead a very religious life;
çok dini bir yaşam sürdüğü insanlar tarafından yapıldı;
those who have been very chaste,
çok iffetli olanlar,
have respected their chastity.
iffetlerine saygı duydum.
But now as you are saints,
Ama şimdi aziz olduğunuza göre,
before you everything is pure and good,
senden önce her şey saf ve güzel
because now you have been leading a saintly life.
çünkü şimdi aziz bir yaşam sürüyorsun.
That's why chastity has become awakened in you,
Bu yüzden iffet senin içinde uyandı,
and chastity works in you as Gauri, as your kundalini.
iffet sizin içinde Gauri, kundalini'niz olarak çalışır.
So if you come to the essence of religious life,
Öyleyse, dini yaşamın özüne gelirseniz,
of righteous life, of Sahaja Yoga life, is chastity.
doğru yaşamın, Sahaja Yoga yaşamının, iffet.
You cannot diversify it.
Çeşitlendiremezsiniz.
Now this chastity gives you the maryadas,
Şimdi bu iffet size maryadas veriyor.
means delimits you.
seni sınırlandırıyor demektir.
(Why are you sitting here?
(Neden burada oturuyorsun?
Go further, it's better to be in front.
Daha ileri gitmek, önünde olmak daha iyi.
This is - you are not doing the puja.
Bu - sen puja yapmıyorsun.
If you are doing the puja, then you sit here.
Eğer puja yapıyorsanız, o zaman buraya oturun.
Otherwise, better sit down.
Aksi takdirde, otursan iyi olur.
Better get My vibrations there,
Titreşimlerim orada olsun,
in front. Here, come along.)
önünde. İşte, hadi gel.)
So the chastity is the one that gives you maryadas,
Yani iffet size maryadas verendir,
gives you the limits.
size sınırları verir.
How does it give you the limits?
Size sınırları nasıl veriyor?
Like the, in the sky is the lightning.
Gibi, gökyüzünde yıldırım.
When the two clouds,
Ne zaman iki bulut
who are like Sahaja yogis we can say,
Söyleyebileceğimiz Sahaja Yogiler gibi,
came out of the sea
denizden geldi
and pure water is
ve saf su
there in the, those clouds,
orada, o bulutlar,
and they have to be poured out;
ve dökülmeleri gerekir;
when they come closer together
birbirlerine yaklaştığında
and cross their limits of their ego,
ve egolarının sınırlarını aşmak,
or fight with each other or in any way clash,
veya birbirleriyle ya da herhangi bir şekilde çatışmasıyla savaşmak,
is, there is this chastity,
bu iffet var,
this lightning that takes place.
bu yıldırım gerçekleşiyor.
This lightning which says that
Bu yıldırım diyor ki
"You are wrong. Why are you fighting among yourself?
“Yanılıyorsun. Neden kendi aralarında kavga ediyorsun?
Why are you crossing each other's ego?"
Neden birbirinizin egosunu geçiyorsunuz? ”
That's the sister's job.
Bu kız kardeşinin işi.
Yesterday we have had many sisters.
Dün birçok kız kardeşimiz oldu.
Now the sister's job is not to take sides,
Şimdi kız kardeşinin işi taraf tutmak değil.
but to show that if you cross your limits
ama eğer sınırlarını aşarsan bunu göstermek için
of your brotherliness,
kardeşliğinin,
then there will be a lightning.
o zaman bir yıldırım olacak.
Now this power of lightning
Şimdi bu yıldırım gücü
is a part of the power of Shri Krishna
Shri Krishna'nın gücünün bir parçası
which He took it out from Himself.
ki onu kendisinden aldı.
That's why He became such a sweet,
Bu yüzden çok tatlı biri oldu.
gentle incarnation.
hafif enkarnasyon.
He took it out.
Dışarı çıkardı.
He said, "Now you've become My sister,
"Şimdi kız kardeşim oldun" dedi.
and every time they try to misbehave you better work it out.
ve her zaman sizi yaramazlık etmeye çalışırlarsa, daha iyi çalışın.
And that's how Shri Krishna became such a gentle and a very,
Ve Shri Krishna böyle nazik ve çok ...
as they call it, romantic incarnation;
dedikleri gibi romantik enkarnasyon;
because He took out the sisterly part away
çünkü kızkardeş kısmını uzaklaştırdı
and He worked it out.
ve o çalıştı.
But She was always with Him
Ama O her zaman Yanındaydı
and She worked with Him;
ve onunla çalıştı;
because the sister in the family
çünkü ailedeki kız kardeşi
has to see that the brothers don't fight,
Kardeşlerin kavga etmediğini görmeli,
they are all looked after well,
hepsine iyi bakılıyor,
that they are not challenged by others,
başkaları tarafından itiraz edilmediklerini,
that she gives them the maryadas
Onlara denizciler verdi
how far to go - how far to go.
ne kadar uzağa - ne kadar uzağa.
Now it's very important,
Şimdi çok önemli
very, very important for all of us to understand
hepimizin anlaması için çok, çok önemli
that Freud and all these nonsensical people
Bu Freud ve tüm bu saçma sapan insanlar
brought forth the theories to challenge Vishnumaya,
Vishnumaya’ya meydan okumak için teorileri ortaya koydu,
so that we should have all kinds of funny relationships,
her türlü komik ilişkiye girmeliyiz,
which is an impossibility,
hangi bir imkansızlık,
is a wrong thing.
yanlış bir şey.
Now if there is any relationship like that
Şimdi, böyle bir ilişki varsa
between brothers and sisters,
kardeşler arasında
for seven generations the family suffers
Yedi nesiller boyunca aile acı çekiyor
from terrible diseases - seven generations.
korkunç hastalıklardan - yedi kuşak.
But if there's another like Freud-style relationship,
Fakat Freud tarzı bir ilişki daha varsa,
then fourteen generations the family has to suffer.
o zaman on dört kuşak ailenin acı çekmesi gerekiyor.
So the limiting forces of Vishnumaya are such
Yani Vishnumaya'nın sınırlayıcı güçleri böyle
that your ego is controlled, your superego is controlled,
egonun kontrol edildiğini, süperegonun kontrol edildiğini,
your family is controlled.
ailen kontrol ediliyor.
Everybody is under control,
Herkes kontrol altında
under the guidance of this pure power of Vishnumaya
Vishnumaya'nın bu saf gücünün rehberliğinde
which exists within all of us.
ki hepimiz içinde var olan.
And the saddest part is that
Ve en üzücü kısmı şu ki
in all the Western countries
tüm batı ülkelerinde
Vishnumaya is sick, absolutely sick.
Vishnumaya hasta, kesinlikle hasta.
I mean, I have lost My hearing even,
Demek istediğim, işitme duyumu bile kaybettim.
up to that point it has come,
o noktaya kadar geldi,
on the left-hand side,
sol tarafta,
because the sense of chastity is completely lacking.
çünkü iffet duygusu tamamen yoksundur.
We have to forget about the people now
Şimdi insanları unutmalıyız.
who have no sense at all, but now we are Sahaja yogis.
hiç bir anlamı yok, ama şimdi biz Sahaja Yogiyiz.
So coming to the right point, we have to say that,
Yani doğru noktaya gelince, şunu söylemeliyiz ki
that many people have still some lingering funny ideas,
birçok insanın hala bazı komik fikirleri olduğunu,
like "I have a good friendship with that gentleman"
"O beyefendi ile iyi bir arkadaşlığım var" gibi
or "I'm very friendly with such and such gentleman"
veya "Böyle ve böyle bir beyefendi ile çok cana yakın"
and all that.
ve hepsi.
It's not a maryada then.
O zaman bir maryada değil.
You cannot have friendship with - between men and women,
Erkeklerle kadınlar arasında arkadaşlık edemezsin.
you cannot, it's absolutely absurd.
yapamazsın, kesinlikle saçma.
In the West the whole culture is funny;
Batı'da bütün kültür komik;
because if you go to a dinner party
çünkü bir akşam yemeğine gidersen
you are supposed to sit with somebody's husband
birinin kocasının yanında oturman gerekiyordu
on both the sides - horrible!
iki tarafta - korkunç!
But in the East it's not done,
Ancak Doğu'da bitmedi
because the Vishnumaya is against these things.
Çünkü Vishnumaya bunlara karşı.
She will see to it that husband and wife sit together.
Karı koca birlikte oturduğunu görecek.
Now here, as you know, the chastity part
Şimdi burada, bildiğiniz gibi, iffet bölümü
is so much missing
çok eksik
that our left Vishuddhis are catching.
soldaki Vishuddhis'in yakaladığı.
And when I talk about it, it catches more.
Ve bunun hakkında konuştuğumda, daha fazlasını yakalar.
Now when you say you are not guilty,
Şimdi suçlu olmadığını söylediğinde,
you are actually admitting it to Vishnumaya,
Aslında bunu Vishnumaya'ya kabul ediyorsun.
to your own sister,
kendi kız kardeşine
saying that "I am not guilty."
"Ben suçlu değilim" diyerek.
But She doesn't like you to have the guilt upon you.
Ama senden suçluluk duymanı istemiyor.
The wife may like you to have the guilt.
Karısı suçluluk duymanı beğenebilir.
She may like that you should have the guilt,
Suçluluk duymanız hoşunuza gidebilir.
because she thinks her power is challenged
çünkü gücünün zor olduğunu düşünüyor
and that she has somebody who is her rival.
ve onun rakibi olan birine sahip olması.
But not, not Vishnumaya;
Ancak, Vishnumaya değil;
the sister does not say that.
kız kardeş bunu söylemez.
But a brother and a sister are never friends.
Fakat bir erkek kardeş ve bir kız kardeş asla arkadaş olmazlar.
Now in a group we are sitting here.
Şimdi bir grupta burada oturuyoruz.
Like that, in any group a brother and a sister,
Bunun gibi, herhangi bir grupta bir erkek kardeş ve bir kız kardeş
they are, they know that they exist as brothers and sisters
onlar, kardeş olarak var olduklarını biliyorlar.
but they don't cling onto one person,
ama bir kişiye yapışmazlar,
they don't talk to one person,
bir kişiyle konuşmuyorlar
they don't get friendly with that sister.
o kız kardeşle arkadaşlık kurmuyorlar.
Like once we had a big fate with these Christians once,
Bir zamanlar bu Hristiyanlarla bir zamanlar büyük bir kaderimiz vardı.
I remember, and I must be having at least
Hatırlıyorum ve en azından sahip olmalıyım.
thirty cousins and four, five brothers I had at that time.
otuz kuzenim ve o zamanlar dört, beş erkek kardeşim vardı.
And we went to that function,
Ve biz bu işleve gittik,
and among Indian Christians
ve Hintli Hristiyanlar arasında
we have Christians from all kinds of stratas.
Her çeşit tabakadan Hristiyan var.
So there were some vagabonds I think,
Yani bence bazı vagabonds vardı,
they passed some remarks about us,
Bizim hakkımızda bazı açıklamalar yaptılar.
we sisters, you see.
Biz kardeşiz, görüyorsunuz.
We didn't know we had so many cousins.
Çok fazla kuzenimiz olduğunu bilmiyorduk.
They all shot out, you see, just like jack-in-the-box,
Hepsi vuruldu, görüyorsun, aynen kutuda olduğu gibi,
and they all took over and started beating those boys.
hepsi devraldı ve o çocukları dövmeye başladı.
And then we realized so many cousins we have.
Ve sonra çok kuzenimiz olduğunu farkettik.
Otherwise we never knew;
Aksi takdirde asla bilmiyorduk;
they were somewhere, we were not talking to them much,
onlar bir yerdeydi, onlarla fazla konuşmadık.
we were talking among ourselves, our friends,
kendi aramızda konuşuyorduk, arkadaşlarımız,
we girls were talking to each other.
biz kızlar birbirimizle konuşuyorduk.
Suddenly we found we have so many cousins
Birdenbire çok fazla kuzenimiz olduğunu gördük.
and so many brothers. It was most surprising
ve pek çok kardeş. En şaşırtıcıydı
that we should have so many cousins there
orada o kadar çok kuzen olmalıyız ki
we did not know.
bilmiyorduk.
Immediately they jumped on the protection
Hemen korumaya atladılar
of the chastity of their sister,
kız kardeşlerinin iffetinin,
because she is the basis of their chastity.
çünkü iffetlerinin temelidir.
But normally you don't talk to your brother much,
Ama normalde kardeşinle fazla konuşmuyorsun.
nor the brother talks to you so much,
ne de abi seninle çok konuşmuyor
you don't get friendly.
Dostça değilsin.
But at the time of difficulties, at the time of maryadas,
Fakat zorluklar sırasında, maryadalar zamanında,
at the time of consulting about something
bir şey hakkında danışma sırasında
that is dear to the family, the sister comes in.
Bu sevgili aileye, kız kardeşi giriyor.
Recently My own brother, younger brother,
Son zamanlarda kendi kardeşim, küçük kardeşim,
wrote a letter to Me
Bana bir mektup yazdı
because there's a problem in the family.
çünkü ailede bir sorun var.
Now My mother is not there, and normally a sister is better
Şimdi annem orada değil ve normalde bir kız kardeş daha iyi
because she is easily available to you than the mother.
çünkü o anneden daha kolay ulaşabiliyor.
Mother is so busy with the whole family,
Annem bütün aile ile çok meşgul.
the whole work, you know what she's doing.
Bütün iş, ne yaptığını biliyorsun.
So the sisterly feeling is very important.
Bu yüzden kardeşçe duygu çok önemlidir.
Now just imagine that our left Vishuddhi is so bad.
Şimdi, sol Vishuddhi'mizin çok kötü olduğunu hayal edin.
It is, of course,
Tabii ki
because we have never cared for our chastity,
çünkü iffetimizi asla önemsemedik,
we have not respected our chastity.
iffetimize saygı göstermedik.
In India it is not so.
Hindistan'da öyle değil.
Women and men all respect their chastity very much.
Kadınlar ve erkekler, iffetlerine çok saygı duyuyorlar.
And I've asked some foreign-going boys,
Ve bazı yabancı erkeklere sordum.
they said that "Though we were doing all wrong things
"Yanlış şeyler yapıyor olsak da" dediler.
as they were doing, we all the time somehow knew
Yaptıkları gibi, her zaman bir şekilde biliyorduk
that we were doing wrong."
yanlış yaptığımızı "
I said, "How is it?"
"Nasıl?" Dedim.
He said, "There's something like a sister's relationship."
"Bir kız kardeşin ilişkisi gibi bir şey var" dedi.
But now I can say that Indian men are also becoming
Ama şimdi Hintli erkeklerin de dönüştüğünü söyleyebilirim.
just like you people,
Tıpkı senin gibi
and have lost their power to keep their chastity.
ve iffetlerini korumak için güçlerini kaybetti.
The men must respect their chastity,
Erkekler iffetlerine saygı duymalı,
because they think they do not owe anything to the chastity.
Çünkü iffet için hiçbir şey borçlu olmadıklarını düşünüyorlar.
And if the basis of your spiritual existence
Ve eğer ruhsal varlığınızın temeli
doesn't exist, you'll collapse in no time.
yok, kısa sürede çökeceksiniz.
For that I have many a times said that
Bunun için bir çok kez söyledim ki
put your attention on the Mother Earth, the green.
dikkatinizi Dünya Ana'ya (yeşil olan) koyun.
Green is the color,
Yeşil renktir,
if you put your attention into that
eğer dikkatini buna koyarsan
then you will be saved
o zaman kurtulacaksın
from these errors you are committing of adultery
bu hatalardan zina etmiş olursun
all the time,
her zaman,
your looking at others' sisters,
Başkalarının kız kardeşlerine bakarken,
others' wives, others' daughters.
başkalarının eşleri, başkalarının kızları.
So the relationship
Yani ilişki
that is now being expressed, as you know,
Bu şimdi bildiğiniz gibi ifade ediliyor
is of a daughter,
bir kızdan
of a sister and of a mother,
Bir kız kardeşi ve bir annenin
which is a very, very pure relationship.
bu çok, çok saf bir ilişki.
So much so that now, supposing you use your brains too much,
Öyle ki, şimdi, beynini çok fazla kullandığını varsayalım.
then why does your heart catch - have you thought of that?
öyleyse neden kalbin yakalar - bunu düşündün mü?
Why does your heart catch when you use right side too much?
Sağ tarafı çok fazla kullandığında neden kalbin kalıyor?
What is the reason for catching your heart?
Kalbini yakalamanın sebebi nedir?
Must understand this, it's the same thing.
Bunu anlamalısınız, aynı şey.
The relationship of, say, Shiva is to Vishnu in two ways.
Diyelim ki Shiva'nın ilişkisi, iki şekilde Vishnu'dur.
Firstly Vishnu's wife - the sister, He has married.
İlk önce Vishnu'nun karısı - kız kardeşi, O evlendi.
All right?
Tamam?
Then who is the sister of Shiva?
O zaman Shiva'nın kız kardeşi kim?
Shiva's sister is Saraswati.
Shiva'nın kız kardeşi Saraswati.
If you work too much on Saraswati, heart will catch.
Saraswati'de çok fazla çalışırsan, kalp yakalar.
It has maryadas.
Maryadas var.
This is how the intermarriages took place,
Evlilikleri böyle yaptı,
by which the sister's relationship
kız kardeşin ilişkisi
is worked out to keep your maryadas of your chakras.
maryadaşlarınızı çakralarınızdan korumak için çalıştı.
If you cross that,
Eğer onu aşarsan,
you suddenly get into the left or the right
aniden sola ya da sağa girersiniz
because you have crossed the maryadas of that.
çünkü bunun maryadasını aştınız.
Now this sisterly relationship existed
Şimdi bu kardeşçe ilişki vardı
in other incarnations also;
diğer enkarnasyonlarda da;
like Mohammed Sahib
Mohammed Sahib gibi
had a sisterly relationship
kızkardeş ilişkisi vardı
with - actually what we have to say that
ile - aslında bunu söylemek zorundayız
His sister as such was Ali's wife,
Ablası Ali'nin karısıydı.
but She was born to Him as a daughter.
ama Kız olarak O'na doğdu.
So they can be born as the daughter or as the sister.
Böylece kızları veya kız kardeşleri olarak doğabilirler.
She was born as Nanaka's sister, Nanaki.
Nanaka'nın kız kardeşi Nanaki olarak doğdu.
She was born as the daughter of Mohammed Sahib.
Muhammed Sahib'in kızı olarak doğdu.
So it could be a sister or could be
Yani bir kız kardeş olabilir ya da olabilir
the daughter of an incarnation.
bir enkarnasyonun kızı.
But daughter and sister are innocent, pure chastity.
Ama kız ve kız kardeşi masum, saf bir iffet.
Now think of it, that those people
Şimdi düşün, bu insanlar
who cannot understand the importance of chastity,
iffetin önemini anlayamayan,
how can they talk of any laws whatsoever?
Herhangi bir yasadan nasıl bahsediyorlar?
- because "laws" means maryadas,
- çünkü "yasalar" maryadas anlamına geliyor,
and it has the proper sense
ve uygun bir mantıklı
through the power of Vishnumaya.
Vishnumaya'nın gücüyle.
Now you might say that not to steal anybody else's thing
Şimdi kimsenin işini çalmamak için söyleyebilirsiniz.
is also not proper, because it belongs to somebody else.
ayrıca uygun değildir, çünkü başka birine aittir.
But who will tell you?
Ama sana kim söyleyecek?
Who is the one that is going to tell you that this is wrong?
Bunun yanlış olduğunu söyleyecek olan kim?
Of course, there is police, but
Tabii ki polis var ama
who has told?
kim söyledi?
The lawmakers.
Milletvekilleri.
Which part of the unconscious has played is the Vishnumaya;
Bilincin hangi kısmını oynadığı Vishnumaya;
because as soon as you steal something you feel guilty.
çünkü bir şeyi çaldığın anda kendini suçlu hissedersin.
In the law also this word "guilty" is used.
Kanunda ayrıca bu kelime "suçlu" kullanılmaktadır.
And guilty comes from the left side, is Vishnumaya.
Suçluluk sol taraftan geliyor, Vishnumaya.
So how important it is to have a sense of chastity.
Öyleyse iffet duygusuna sahip olmak ne kadar önemli.
But we are very divided people,
Ama biz çok bölünmüş insanlarız.
and those who have moral chastity
ve ahlaki iffet sahip olanlar
may not have material chastity.
maddi iffet olmayabilir.
Those who have got material chastity
Maddi iffet olanlar
may not have moral chastity.
ahlaki iffet olmayabilir.
Moral chastity comes first,
Ahlaki iffet önce gelir,
that's very important,
bu çok önemli
because it is innate.
çünkü doğuştan geldi.
And if your moral chastity is perfectly nourished,
Ve eğer ahlaki iffetiniz tam olarak beslenmişse,
then automatically the material chastity comes in.
sonra otomatik olarak maddi iffet gelir.
But the effect is the same.
Ancak etkisi aynı.
Whether you do money cheating in Sahaja Yoga
Sahaja Yoga'da hile yaparak para kazanın
or whether you cheat morally,
veya ahlaki olarak hile yapıp yapmadığınızı,
your left Vishuddhi will be caught,
sol Vishuddhi yakalanacak
and the whole problem will start from left Vishuddhi.
ve bütün problem sol Vishuddhi'den başlayacak.
Now supposing somebody tries to cheat in Sahaja Yoga,
Şimdi diyelim ki birileri Sahaja Yoga'da hile yapmaya çalışıyor.
want to take away the money of Sahaja Yoga
Sahaja Yoga'nın parasını almak istiyorum
or something like that.
ya da böyle bir şey.
Immediately his left Vishuddhi will be caught.
Hemen solundaki Vishuddhi yakalanacak.
As soon as the left Vishuddhi will be caught
Sol Vishuddhi yakalanır yakalanmaz
he will start behaving in a funny manner,
komik bir şekilde davranmaya başlayacak
the whole catch will be shown.
Bütün yaka gösterilecek.
If you become immoral also
Eğer ahlaksız kalırsan
the left Vishuddhi will be caught.
sol Vishuddhi yakalanacak.
Now the whole guilt part comes from there.
Şimdi bütün suçluluk bölümü oradan geliyor.
Sin against the Mother could be also an insult,
Anneye karşı günah da hakaret olabilir,
in any way answering back to Mother.
Herhangi bir şekilde, Anneme cevap vermek.
Many people have a habit, I've seen, of saying,
Bir çok insanın bir alışkanlığı var, söylediğim gibi,
"No, Mother."
"Hayır anne."
"No" is never to be said,
"Hayır" asla söylenemez
because if you say "no"
çünkü "hayır" dersen
that means you go to the left Vishuddhi.
Bu, soldaki Vishuddhi'ye gideceğiniz anlamına gelir.
The Vishnumaya power will not tolerate your "no"
Vishnumaya'nın gücü "hayır" a dayanamaz
for anything at all.
hiç bir şey için.
Many people have a habit of saying this, "No, Mother."
Birçok insan "Hayır, Anne" deme alışkanlığına sahiptir.
This is not to be done,
Bu yapılmayacak
because once you catch your left Vishuddhi
çünkü bir keresinde sol Vishuddhi'yi yakalarsan
all your left chakras become weak,
tüm sol çakralarınız zayıflar,
because the chastity which is the basis of all the chakras
çünkü tüm çakraların temeli olan iffet
is weak.
Zayıf
So how much important it is
Peki bu ne kadar önemli
to understand the value of left Vishuddhi.
sol Vishuddhi'nin değerini anlamak için.
All of us catch on left Vishuddhi,
Hepimiz sol Vishuddhi'yi yakalarız.
and we do not think that it is such an important thing.
ve bunun önemli bir şey olduğunu düşünmüyoruz.
But we say, "Oh, left Vishuddhi catching
Ama diyoruz ki, "Oh, Vishuddhi'yi yakaladı.
means I'm feeling guilty."
Kendimi suçlu hissettiğim anlamına geliyor. "
We do not understand that "What have I done?
"Ne yaptım ben?" Anlamıyorum.
I have crossed the limits, that's why is showing there.
Sınırları aştım, bu yüzden orada gösteriliyor.
I've neglected some kind of a morality.
Bir tür ahlakı ihmal ettim.
I've gone on a wrong path against Mother
Anneme karşı yanlış yola girdim
and Father, that's why left Vishuddhi's catching."
Baba, bu yüzden Vishuddhi'yi yakaladı. "
Left Vishuddhi is the indication of the mistakes,
Sol Vişuddhi, hataların göstergesidir,
of the wrongs, of the sins.
yanlışlardan, günahlardan.
We can't afford to have left Vishuddhi,
Vishuddhi'den ayrılmayı göze alamayız.
Sahaja yogis cannot afford to have left Vishuddhi.
Sahaja Yogiler Vishuddhi'den ayrılmayı göze alamazlar.
To add to the trouble, they smoke,
Belaya eklemek için, sigara içiyorlar.
they take all kinds of things.
her türlü şeyi alırlar.
In India they take what you call tamakhu,
Hindistan'da tamakhu dediğiniz şeyi alırlar.
is a kind of a - what leaves are these? - tobacco leaves,
bu bir çeşit - bunlar ne? - tütün yaprakları
and they think they have done no wrong.
ve yanlış yapmadıklarını düşünüyorlar.
But left Vishuddhi catches.
Ama sol Vishuddhi yakalar.
Left Vishuddhi, in a way, is the gateway
Sol Vishuddhi, bir şekilde, ağ geçidi
to all kinds of problems for yourself,
Kendin için her türlü soruna,
so be careful not to feel guilty about anything.
bu yüzden hiçbir şey için suçlu hissetmemeye dikkat edin.
Moreover it's a very vicious - great vicious circle.
Üstelik çok kısır - harika bir kısır döngü.
For example, somebody has done something wrong.
Örneğin, birileri yanlış bir şey yaptı.
I have decided that I have to tell them on their face
Onlara yüzlerini anlatmam gerektiğine karar verdim
whether they like it or not, this is wrong,
Sevseler de beğenmeseler de, bu yanlış.
as far as possible. Of course,
olabildiğince uzağa. Tabii ki,
I try to play sometimes tricks on them to understand,
Bazen anlamak için onlara oyun oynamayı deniyorum.
if they do not understand My telling them - up to a point.
anlamıyorlarsa onlara söylemem - bir noktaya kadar.
And then I tell them that "Now you better get out.
Ve sonra onlara "Şimdi çıksan iyi olur" dedim.
I cannot have you in My body any more."
Artık seni Vücudumda tutamam. "
So I throw them out of Sahaja Yoga.
Bu yüzden onları Sahaja Yogadan atıyorum.
Once they're out of Sahaja Yoga at least
En azından Sahaja Yogadan çıktıklarında
My headache is over.
Baş ağrım bitti.
Now what I have seen that
Şimdi ne gördüm ki
when this negativity starts acting, people,
Bu olumsuzluk hareket etmeye başladığında,
instead of facing it, facing the mistakes that "I am wrong,
bununla yüzleşmek yerine, "Ben hatalıyım,
I should not have done it, it's a wrong thing to do,"
Yapmamalıydım, yapılacak yanlış bir şey. "
start giving explanations.
açıklamalar yapmaya başla.
Once you start giving explanation,
Açıklama yapmaya başladığınızda,
this left Vishuddhi starts becoming like a bloated big lump,
Bu sol Vishuddhi şişirilmiş büyük bir topak gibi olmaya başlar,
and then there's no possibility of curing,
ve sonra iyileştirme imkanı yok.
no possibility of cleansing.
temizleme imkanı yok.
So people start giving explanation,
Böylece insanlar açıklama yapmaya başlar.
"Why I did it, why I did this."
"Neden yaptım, neden yaptım?"
Once it is said is wrong, is wrong;
Bir kez söylendiğinde yanlış, yanlış;
to be accepted,
kabul edilmek
"All right, next time I'm not going to do it,
"Tamam, bir dahaki sefere yapmayacağım,
I'm very sorry." But "sorry"
Çok üzgünüm. "Ama" üzgünüm ".
seems to be a very difficult word for at least
en azından çok zor bir kelime gibi görünüyor
Western Sahaja yogis
Batı Sahaja Yogileri
and some of the Indian Sahaja yogis also,
ve Hintli Sahaja Yogilerin bir kısmı da,
to say, "Sorry, I'm very sorry."
"Üzgünüm, çok özür dilerim" demek için.
Indians never feel guilty, is a good idea,
Kızılderililer asla suçlu hissetmez, iyi bir fikirdir.
but they never say sorry, so it's just the same.
ama asla özür dilemiyorlar, bu yüzden aynı.
Now one has to understand
Şimdi birileri anlamak zorunda
that when you have committed a mistake,
Bir hata yaptığında,
you are a human being: to error is human
sen bir insansın: hata yapmak insan
and to forgive, divine.
ve affetmek, ilahi.
But you must know that you have erred.
Ama yanıldığını bilmelisin.
If you go on giving explanations then one thing is definite,
Açıklama yapmaya devam edersen bir şey kesindir,
you do not understand that God knows everything.
Tanrı'nın her şeyi bildiğini anlamıyorsunuz.
If He says you have done wrong, then it is a wrong.
Yanlış yaptığını söylüyorsa, yanlış olur.
How can you challenge, how can you say,
Nasıl meydan okuyabilirsin, nasıl söylersin?
"This is the reason I did it. That's the reason"
“Yapmamın nedeni bu. Sebep bu”
- it's the thing one must understand.
- kişinin anlaması gereken şey.
Because this is the power of electricity,
Çünkü bu elektriğin gücüdür,
you must understand, gives you a shock.
anlamalısınız, size bir şok veriyor.
It shocks you.
Seni şok ediyor.
And then you realize that "I have done a mistake."
Ve sonra "Bir hata yaptım" denin.
So don't create a shock for yourself.
O yüzden kendin için şok yaratma.
Do not behave in a manner
Bir şekilde davranmayın
that ultimately you end up with a shock.
Sonunda bir şok ile sonuçlanır.
It's - of course, the Mother's power is so forgiving,
Elbette, annenin gücü çok bağışlayıcıdır.
Sadashiva's power is so forgiving that you are allowed,
Sadashiva’nın gücü o kadar bağışlayıcı ki,
and allowed, and allowed
ve izin verilen ve izin verilen
to continue with what you are doing, for a while.
Bir süredir yaptıklarına devam etmek için.
But it's been told,
Ama söylendi.
is explained to you that this is wrong.
bunun yanlış olduğu size açıklandı.
But supposing you cross your limits absolutely,
Ama diyelim ki sınırlarını kesinlikle aştın.
then suddenly the Vishnumaya appears
sonra aniden Vishnumaya belirir
and the whole thing gets exposed.
ve her şey açığa çıkar.
In Sahaja Yoga you get exposed.
Sahaja Yoga'da maruz kalıyorsunuz.
So one must know that though this power is so helpful,
Öyleyse, kişi bu gücün çok faydalı olmasına rağmen,
so guiding, so improving and nourishing and protecting,
çok yol gösterici, çok geliştirici ve besleyici ve koruyan
still - up to a point.
hala - bir noktaya kadar.
Otherwise it is She only who exposes you,
Aksi halde, sadece seni ifşa eden kişidir.
because She can't bear any more this nonsense from you.
çünkü senden daha fazla bu saçmalığa tahammül edemiyor.
So if you go on like that,
Yani böyle devam edersen,
She'll just see to it that She is exposed.
Sadece maruz kaldığını görecek.
You have seen people have been doing
İnsanların yaptığını gördün.
all kinds of filthy things.
her türlü pis şey.
I have known many prime ministers
Birçok başbakan tanıdım
and all these presidents and this and that,
ve tüm bu başkanlar ve bu ve
when they die - exposed.
öldüklerinde - maruz kalırlar.
Nobody says that such and such person was a chaste person.
Kimse böyle ve böyle bir kişinin iffetli biri olduğunu söylemez.
Very few leaders of nations have got this certificate
Çok az sayıda ulus lideri bu sertifikaya sahip
that they were very chaste people.
onlar çok iffetli insanlardı.
Chastity is a very, very rare certificate they get.
Bekaret, aldıkları çok, çok nadir bir sertifikadır.
Because once you get a power in life
Çünkü bir kez hayatında bir güç elde edersen
then you think you have a free hand,
o zaman özgür bir elin olduğunu düşünüyorsun,
you can be and you can do what you like.
olabilir ve ne istersen yapabilirsin.
You can be a chaste person,
Sen iffetli biri olabilirsin.
you can be any way unchaste,
herhangi bir şekilde kaygısız olabilirsin,
you can do what you like.
ne istersen yapabilirsin.
You become sort of overpowered with this idea that
Bu fikirle aşırı güçleniyorsun.
"I have got all the powers, now I am very well placed."
“Tüm güçlere sahibim, şimdi çok iyi yerleştirildim.”
And that becomes a complete delusion for you,
Ve bu senin için tam bir hayal oldu,
and you forget that chastity is so important.
ve iffetin çok önemli olduğunu unutuyorsun.
So the higher a person is placed in life,
Bu yüzden, bir insan hayatına yerleştirilir,
the higher positions he occupies,
işgal ettiği yüksek pozisyonlar,
the higher what you call the ego-pampering stuff he gets,
Ne kadar yükselirse, onun aldığı ego şımartan
the more he presses down on the left Vishuddhi.
sol Vishuddhi'ye daha fazla baskı yapar.
So such a person escapes into the left Vishuddhi,
Böylece böyle bir insan sol Vishuddhi'ye kaçar.
because in his heart of hearts,
çünkü kalbinin kalbinde,
in his unconscious he feels guilty.
bilinçaltında kendini suçlu hissediyor.
And the whole thing goes as a guilt,
Ve her şey suçluluk duygusuyla gider.
guilt in the left Vishuddhi.
sol Vishuddhi içinde suçluluk.
And when it goes as a guilt in the left Vishuddhi
Ve sol Vishuddhi bir suçluluk olarak gittiğinde
then it's a difficult situation,
o zaman zor bir durum
because such a person,
çünkü böyle bir insan
he becomes extremely sensitive.
son derece hassas hale geldi.
You say anything to that person, he feels more guilty.
O kişiye bir şey söylersen kendini daha suçlu hisseder.
You try to cure his left Vishuddhi,
Solundaki Vishuddhi'yi iyileştirmeye çalışıyorsun.
then he becomes even worse.
o zaman daha da kötüleşiyor.
It's a very bad situation with left Vishuddhi people,
Bu sol Vishuddhi insanlarla çok kötü bir durum,
and they are the people who have left Vishuddhi
ve onlar Vishuddhi'yi terk eden insanlar.
always give explanations.
her zaman açıklamalarda bulun.
A person who has right Vishuddhi will be arrogant,
Doğru Vishuddhi olan bir kişi kibirli olacak,
but left Vishuddhi people have a very sly method
ama sol Vishuddhi insanlar çok sinsi bir yöntemi var
of giving answers back and explanation for everything.
cevapların geri verilmesi ve her şeyin açıklaması.
Whatever You say, they will say,
Ne söylersen söylerler
"No, Mother, this is this, this is this."
"Hayır anne, bu, bu, bu."
This is one thing. Not only, it doesn't end there,
Bu bir şey. Sadece orada bitmiyor,
it gives you sarcasm.
sana iğneleme veriyor.
That's why in the West people never talk straightforward,
Bu yüzden Batı'da insanlar asla doğrudan konuşmadılar.
it's always sarcastic.
her zaman alaycı.
To talk straightforward means they think it's stupid,
Açık konuşmak, aptalca olduğunu düşünüyor.
is unintelligent,
akıllıca,
if unless and until you talk in a very sarcastic manner
eğer alaycı bir şekilde konuşmazsanız
which sometimes, you know, it's difficult to reach.
ki bazen, bilirsin, ulaşmak zordur.
That's how in a very crooked way they talk.
Çok çarpık bir şekilde konuşurlar.
And that crookery comes through this left Vishuddhi problem.
Ve bu sahtekarlık bu sol Vishuddhi probleminden geliyor.
If your left Vishuddhi is so bad,
Sol Vishuddhi çok kötüyse,
you cannot achieve anything that is sweet,
tatlı bir şey elde edemezsin
that is beautiful,
Bu güzel,
that's appreciative.
bu minnettar.
Left Vishuddhi will never appreciate.
Sol Vishuddhi asla takdir etmeyecek.
Those who suffer from left Vishuddhi
Acı çekenler Vishuddhi'den ayrıldılar
can never appreciate another person, can never.
başka birini asla takdir edemez, asla edemez.
It will have its own say, it will think, "I'm the best"
Kendi deyişine sahip olacak, "Ben en iyisiyim" diye düşünecek.
because it has to exist,
çünkü var olmalı
that problem has to exist, so how?
bu sorunun var olması gerekiyor, peki nasıl?
It's a kind of a perverted ego
Bu bir tür sapkın ego
that doesn't want to accept
kabul etmek istemiyor
that anybody can be better than me,
herhangi birinin benden daha iyi olabileceğini,
that anybody I have to follow,
takip etmem gereken herkes,
that I have to take some lessons from another one.
başka birinden bazı dersler almam gerekiyor.
I've had many examples;
Bir çok örneğim oldu;
I see specially people who are with Me,
Özel olarak benimle birlikte olan insanları görüyorum.
I find they get into left Vishuddhi very fast
Vishuddhi'yi çok çabuk sola soktuklarını biliyorum.
because they lack in protocol.
çünkü protokolde eksikler.
Once they start lacking in protocol
Bir kez protokolde eksik kalmaya başladılar
they go into left Vishuddhi.
sola Vishuddhi'ye giderler.
So to be with Me is a blessing, no doubt,
Öyleyse Benimle olmak bir nimettir, şüphesiz,
but also one has to be very, very careful
ama aynı zamanda çok, çok dikkatli olmak zorunda
that you do not cross the protocols.
protokolleri geçmediğini
Do not try to come over-forward,
İleri gelmeyi denemeyin
just prancing.
Sadece Şahlanan.
Some people have a habit of crossing the limits,
Bazı insanların sınırları aşma alışkanlığı vardır,
and as soon as you cross the limits
ve sınırları aşar geçmez
left Vishuddhi is created.
sol Vishuddhi yaratıldı.
There should be awe for your Mother,
Annen için huşu olmalı.
there should be respect for your Mother,
Annene saygı duyulmalı,
which is guarded by left Vishuddhi.
sol Vishuddhi tarafından korunmaktadır.
Now this is a very hidden power of Shri Ganesha.
Şimdi bu Shri Ganesha'nın çok gizli bir gücü.
What you call is the power of Ganesha
Ne diyorsun Ganesha'nın gücü
is left Vishuddhi acting like chastity.
Vishuddhi'nin iffet gibi davranmasıyla kaldı.
Ganesha's power are all expressed through left Vishuddhi.
Ganesha'nın gücü tamamen sol Vishuddhi ile ifade edilir.
So those who believe in Ganesha, in pure innocence,
Yani Ganesha’ya inananlar, saf masumiyette,
must know that in your everyday-to-day behavior,
günlük davranışlarınızda bunu bilmeli
in everyday-to-day action,
günlük eylemlerde,
there should be chastity.
iffet olmalı.
Ganesha is expressed as flowers of chastity.
Ganesha, iffet çiçekleri olarak ifade edilir.
And just see, in the divine law if there's no chastity,
Gördüğünüz gibi ilahi hukukta bir iffet yoksa,
how do you delimit people,
İnsanları nasıl sınırlandırıyorsunuz?
how do you make all right,
nasıl iyileşirsiniz
how do you cleanse them,
Onları nasıl temizlersiniz?
how do you make them evolve?
Onları nasıl geliştirirsiniz?
Supposing a tree is growing and there's no limit in it,
Bir ağacın büyümekte olduğunu ve içinde bir sınır olmadığını varsayalım.
it just grows like a wild thing,
vahşi bir şey gibi büyüyor,
it has no limits,
sınırı yok,
then what will you get out of it?
o zaman ondan ne çıkacaksın?
Nothing.
Hiçbir şey değil.
So to make a person higher and higher,
Böylece bir insanı daha yükseğe çıkarmak için,
you have to limit it.
sınırlaman gerekiyor.
My father used to give a very good example of this,
Babam buna çok iyi bir örnek verirdi.
that if you take some wheat, the wheat &amp; .
Bazı buğday alırsanız, buğday ve.
(You please now don't disturb.
(Lütfen şimdi rahatsız etmeyin.
If you want to go out you can go out,
Dışarı çıkmak istiyorsan dışarı çıkabilirsin.
but don't disturb the people, anybody moving about.)
ama insanları rahatsız etmeyin, etrafta dolaşan herhangi biri.)
This is also another thing is, you see.
Bu da başka bir şey, görüyorsunuz.
All these things are nothing but
Bütün bunlar başka bir şey değil
the upheaval of the left Vishuddhi.
sol Vishuddhi'nin ayaklanması.
See, all this show-off or disturbing
Bütün bu şovlar ya da rahatsız edici şeyleri görün.
or trying to be overpowering,
ya da güçlendirici olmaya çalışıyor,
or very forward person or bumptiousness,
veya çok ileri kişi veya kabadayılık,
all these come from left Vishuddhi,
Bütün bunlar sol Vishuddhi'den geliyor.
because you want to overcome your left Vishuddhi
Çünkü sol Vishuddhi'nin üstesinden gelmek istiyorsun.
so you do it.
yani sen yap.
And then this is added to it.
Ve sonra bu buna eklenir.
The more you try to overcome it, the more it is added to it.
Ne kadar üstesinden gelirsen, o kadar fazla eklenir.
Now the father's story I must tell you,
Şimdi babanın hikayesi sana söylemeliyim,
that he said that
o dedi ki
you have got the wheat and if you spread it,
buğdayı aldınız ve eğer yaysanız
it just fritters away like attention does.
sadece dikkat ettiği gibi börek yapıyor.
But if you put in a gunny bag,
Ama eğer topal bir çantaya koyarsan,
in a bag,
çantada,
you can heap it up and it can achieve a height.
Yığınlayabilirsiniz ve bir yükseklik elde edebilirsiniz.
In the same way,
Aynı şekilde,
if you fritter away your attention without chastity,
eğer iffet etmeden dikkatinizi dağıtırsanız,
it spreads out;
yayılır;
it has no limits, it has no forms,
sınırları yok, formları yok,
it had no shape.
şekli yoktu.
But if you delimit it,
Ama sınırlandırırsan,
then you become higher and higher and higher,
o zaman daha da yükselir, yükselir ve yükselir,
and you can rise higher in your spiritual life.
ve ruhsal yaşamınızda daha yükseğe çıkabilirsiniz.
As you are the people who want to lead a very spiritual life,
Sizler çok manevi bir yaşam sürmek isteyen insanlar olduğunuz için,
you must understand that left Vishuddhi is to be corrected.
sol Vishuddhi'nin düzeltilmesi gerektiğini anlamalısın.
Now, how do you correct your left Vishuddhi?
Şimdi, sol Vishuddhi'nizi nasıl düzeltirsiniz?
I get sometimes very tired with them,
Bazen onlardan çok yoruluyorum.
really to be - I get very,
Gerçekten olmak - Ben çok alıyorum
I just give them up.
Onları sadece bırakıyorum.
Because if they are catching
Çünkü yakalamak istiyorlarsa
and you tell them "You are catching"
ve sen onlara "Yakaladığını" söylüyorsun.
they become even worse. What a vicious circle it is.
daha da kötüleşiyorlar. Ne kadar da kısır bir döngü.
What is the cure for it?
Bunun tedavisi nedir?
How to break the vicious circle? - is by facing it.
Kısır döngü nasıl kırılır? - yüzleşerek.
Should say, "What, you are feeling guilty for what?
"Ne, ne için suçluluk hissediyorsunuz?
You're doing the same mistake again and again,
Aynı hatayı tekrar tekrar yapıyorsun.
and still you're doing it."
ve hala yapıyorsun. "
You should give all injections to yourself.
Tüm enjeksiyonları kendine vermelisin.
But instead of that they start telling Me,
Ama bunun yerine Bana anlatmaya başlarlar.
"No, Mother. No, Mother. No, Mother."
"Hayır, anne. Hayır, anne. Hayır, anne."
You tell yourself, "No, myself.
Kendine, "Hayır, kendim" de.
I have done this today, tomorrow I'm going to do it,
Bunu bugün yaptım, yarın yapacağım.
day after tomorrow I'm going to do it.
yarından sonraki gün yapacağım.
Stop it now, stop." And stop at this point.
Şimdi durdur, dur. "Ve bu noktada dur.
There you exert your Vishnumaya power.
Orada Vishnumaya gücünüzü kullanıyorsunuz.
Vishnumaya power has to be neutralized,
Vishnumaya gücünün etkisiz hale getirilmesi gerekiyor,
if so, by your mistakes;
öyleyse, yanlışlarınızla;
but if it has to be brought back into its power,
ama onun gücüne geri getirilmesi gerekiyorsa,
you must use Vishnumaya's power
Vishnumaya'nın gücünü kullanmalısın
by giving yourself shocks.
Kendine şok vererek.
Then only you can do it.
O zaman sadece sen yapabilirsin.
So on that point, on the Vishnumaya point
Yani bu noktada, Vishnumaya noktasında
I really fail you.
Seni gerçekten başarısızlığa uğrattım.
You have to do it.
Bunu yapmak zorundasın.
And that's why I was thinking about this puja
Bu yüzden bu pujayı düşünüyordum.
that when you people are doing this puja to Me,
Siz ikiniz bana bu pujayı yaparken,
if I say anything it will create more Vishnumaya in you.
Eğer bir şey söylersem, daha çok Vishnumaya yaratacak.
But that's the easiest way to manage things, you see -
Fakat olayları yönetmenin en kolay yolu, görüyorsunuz -
"I am feeling guilty" - you're finished.
"Kendimi suçlu hissediyorum" - işin bitti.
"I have taken the punishment, I called myself guilty."
"Cezayı çektim, kendimi suçlu çağırdım."
It's like in the court the jury says you are guilty
Mahkemede olduğu gibi jüri suçlu olduğunu söylüyor
- all right, accept it, "I am guilty," but no punishment,
- Tamam, kabul et, "Suçluyum", ancak ceza yok.
take no punishment.
ceza alma.
If you have done wrong, then punish yourself.
Eğer yanlış yaptıysan, kendini cezalandır.
Now there are two ways people punish.
Şimdi insanların cezalandırmanın iki yolu var.
One is like some people punish them
Bir tanesi bazı insanlar onları cezalandırıyor gibi
by saying that "I will not have my food."
"Yemeğimi yemeyeceğim" diyerek.
But those people who have a habit of not having food
Ancak yemek yememe alışkanlığı olan insanlar
and this thing, can also become aggressive
ve bu şey, ayrıca agresif olabilir
with that kind of a habit to trouble others
başkalarını rahatsız etmek için bu tür bir alışkanlık ile
by not eating food. I mean, human beings are very crooked.
yemek yemeden. Demek istediğim, insanlar çok çarpık.
They know how to kill themselves
Kendilerini nasıl öldüreceklerini biliyorlar.
with a crooked knife all the time.
her zaman çarpık bir bıçakla.
So that's not the way you can correct yourself.
Demek kendini düzeltmenin yolu bu değil.
If you have to correct yourself,
Kendini düzeltmek zorunda kalırsan,
then you have to face yourself in a proper way.
o zaman kendine uygun bir şekilde yüzleşmelisin.
Supposing you have done something wrong,
Diyelim ki yanlış bir şey yaptınız.
then you should do something that
o zaman böyle bir şey yapmalısın
you would like to do normally,
normal olarak yapmak istersin
and punish yourself.
ve kendini cezalandır.
You should, you should, I am sorry,
Yapmalısın, yapmalısın, üzgünüm,
you should not do something
bir şey yapmamalısın
that you would like to do normally.
normal olarak yapmak istediğini
Like correcting yourself;
Kendini düzeltmek gibi;
somebody is, say, very fond of the gardens, of flowers.
Birisi bahçelere, çiçeklere çok düşkün.
When you do some mistake
Hata yaptığın zaman
you don't see flowers for some time,
bir süre çiçek görmüyorsun,
just close your eyes for flowers.
sadece çiçekler için gözlerini kapat.
Now there are some people, supposing,
Şimdi, varsayalım ki bazı insanlar var.
who are fond of singing,
şarkı söylemeyi çok seven
so if you do mistakes then just stop singing.
eğer hata yaparsan şarkı söylemeyi kes.
That's how you have to shock.
Şok yapman gereken bu.
You must know Vishnumaya is a lightning,
Vishnumaya'nın bir yıldırım olduğunu bilmelisin.
and the lecture has to be like that.
ve ders böyle olmalı.
It cannot be that soft one, as Shri Krishna was.
Shri Krishna'nın olduğu kadar yumuşak biri olamaz.
It's a very powerful thing I'm telling you,
Sana anlattığım çok güçlü bir şey.
and may God awaken that power within you of Vishnumaya.
ve Tanrı, Vishnumaya'nın içindeki bu gücü uyandırabilir.
It's the most powerful thing that a human being can have,
Bir insanın sahip olabileceği en güçlü şey,
is the most auspicious thing;
en hayırlı şey;
you become a holy personality.
Kutsal bir kişilik haline geliyorsun.
This is one of the ways of getting God's realization.
Bu, Tanrı'nın idrakini gerçekleştirmenin yollarından biridir.
It was a nice question aptly asked,
Uygun bir şekilde sorulan hoş bir soruydu.
right time yesterday,
dün doğru zaman,
is to establish your chastity
iffetinizi kurmak
- not by giving bandhans,
- Bandhaneler vererek değil,
taking vibrations from Mother and then getting lost,
Anneden titreşimler alıp kaybolmak,
not that way: you yourself correcting yourself
bu şekilde değil: kendin düzeltiyorsun
morning till evening,
sabahtan akşama kadar
and facing yourself and not feeling guilty,
ve kendinle yüzleşmek ve suçlu hissetmemek,
and learning new things.
ve yeni şeyler öğrenmek.
All the time is the sister who teaches you,
Her zaman sana öğreten kız kardeş
all the time, how to be better and better and better,
Her zaman, nasıl daha iyi ve daha iyi ve daha iyi olmak,
not the Mother;
Anne değil;
because Mother you can say, "No, Mother."
Çünkü Anne, "Hayır, Anne" diyebilirsiniz.
To a sister if you say - electricity,
Söylersen bir kız kardeşine - elektrik,
all right?
tamam?
Try your fingers in the plug and you will know
Parmaklarınızı fişe takmayı deneyin;
- no explanations!
- açıklama yok!
With this understanding,
Bu anlayışla,
today we are going to do the puja
bugün pujayı yapacağız
for the establishment of our chastity,
iffetimizin kurulması için,
chastity of our emotions and chastity of our mind.
duygularımızın iffetini ve zihnimizin iffetini.
Now whatever you have done so far,
Şimdiye dek ne yaptıysan,
forget it, forget the past.
Unut gitsin, geçmişi unut.
That is very important also to forget the past,
Geçmişi unutmak da çok önemli.
because you see that's a very good way of explaining,
çünkü bunun açıklamanın çok iyi bir yolu olduğunu görüyorsunuz.
"Because I had this, that's why it has happened.
“Çünkü bunu yaptım, bu yüzden oldu.
My mother was like this, that, and my father was like this
Annem böyleydi ve babam böyleydi.
"Mother, father, everybody you forget now,
"Anne, baba, şimdi unuttuğun herkes,
you belong to this family, which is a holy family.
Sen kutsal bir aile olan bu aileye aitsin.
People who are saints
Aziz olan insanlar
sitting here, among them you are.
Burada otururken, onların arasındasınız.
And automatically these laws will start working,
Ve otomatik olarak bu yasalar çalışmaya başlayacak,
and I will not have to tell you
ve sana söylemek zorunda kalmayacağım
whether you be friendly with that person
o kişiyle dost olup olmadığına bakma
or not friendly with that person.
ya da o kişiyle dost değil.
You see, interest in another sex
Görüyorsun, başka bir cinsiyete ilgi
all the time is not a sign of chastity.
her zaman bir iffet işareti değildir.
I mean, it's horrid, absolutely ridiculous,
Yani, korkunç, kesinlikle saçma.
you become stupid.
aptal oldun
Like some men know so much about what women use,
Bazı erkeklerin kadınların ne kullandığı hakkında çok şey bildiği gibi
perfumes, this, that. What's the use?
parfümler, bu, bu. Kullanımı nedir?
Are you slaves of women, or what?
Kadın kölesi misiniz yoksa ne?
They become experts on this nonsensical thing.
Bu saçma sapan şey konusunda uzmanlaşıyorlar.
You are men, live like men.
Sen erkeksin, erkekler gibi yaşa.
And women have to have that sense of chastity
Ve kadınlar bu iffet duygusuna sahip olmalılar.
within themselves, because they're the powers.
kendi içlerinde, çünkü onlar güçler.
Why are you wanting to become like men?
Neden erkekler gibi olmak istiyorsun?
I mean, you are the powers behind them.
Demek istediğim, sen onların arkasındaki güçlerin.
And women must look after their chastity.
Kadınlar da iffetleriyle ilgilenmeliler.
For that I must say,
Bunun için söylemeliyim ki
I must bow to Indian women for that,
Bunun için Hintli kadınlara boyun eğmeliyim.
the way they are humble,
alçak gönüllü olmaları,
the way they are chaste,
iffetli olmaları,
one has to learn - of course there are many
birinin öğrenmesi gerekiyor - elbette çok fazla var
who are not also - but the humility that they have.
kim değil - ama sahip oldukları alçakgönüllülük.
There's only one category which should not have humility:
Alçakgönüllülüğü olmaması gereken tek bir kategori var:
that is the incarnations.
bu enkarnasyonlardır.
I cannot have humility, sorry to say.
Alçakgönüllülük edemem, özür dilerim.
There are certain qualities you can have
Sahip olabileceğin bazı özellikler var.
and enjoy and cherish, I cannot have.
ve zevk ve beslemek, sahip olamam.
I cannot humble down Myself, cannot do it, I'm sorry
Alçak gönüllü olamam Kendim, yapamam, özür dilerim
- I'm not supposed to do it.
- Yapmamam gerekiyordu.
No incarnation was humble;
Hiçbir enkarnasyon mütevazı değildi;
they cannot,
yapamazlar,
because they have no guilt.
Çünkü suçlulukları yok.
I have put so many guilty people in My left Vishuddhi
Soldaki Vishuddhi'ye çok fazla suçlu insan koydum
that My ears are getting blocked trying to clear them out.
Onları temizlemeye çalışırken kulaklarım tıkalı.
If you can clear out your guilt
Suçluluğunu silebilirsen
My ears will be opened out, My trouble will go away.
Kulaklarım açılacak, benim sorunum yok olacak.
So please, I request you
Lütfen rica ediyorum
to keep your left Vishuddhi all right.
sol Vishuddhi'nizi iyi tutmak için.
Don't feel guilty, be in the center.
Suçluluk hissetme, merkezde ol.
Be in the center, watch yourself and face yourself,
Merkezde ol, kendini izle ve kendinle yüzleş,
shock yourself, correct yourself.
Kendini şok et, kendini düzelt.
Only such people will ascend.
Sadece bu insanlar yükselecek.
Another way is meditation.
Başka bir yol meditasyondur.
With your left hand towards the photograph,
Sol eliniz fotoğrafa doğru
with the light there, right hand on the Mother Earth,
oradaki ışıkla, Toprak Ana'nın sağ elinde,
you can work it out.
Bunu çözebilirsin.
Put the light over here,
Işıkları buraya koy.
give a bandhan to your left Vishuddhi,
sol Vishuddhi’nize bir bandhan verin.
you can work it out.
Bunu çözebilirsin.
But these become rituals if you do not do it from your heart.
Ancak bunu kalbinizden yapmazsanız bunlar ritüel olur.
So first of all face it, mentally face it fully,
Öncelikle onunla yüzleş, zihinsel olarak onunla yüzleş.
then do it with these things.
o zaman bu şeylerle yapın.
Emotionally understand it also,
Duygusal olarak da anlayın,
that the emotions you have should have no guilt in it.
Sahip olduğun duyguların içinde hiçbir suçluluk olmamalı.
So for all our practical purposes
Yani tüm pratik amaçlarımız için
we are not to use all such words which shows our guilt
suçluluğumuzu gösteren tüm bu kelimeleri kullanmayacağız
- but humility.
- ama alçakgönüllülük.
Humility is very different from a guilty person.
Alçakgönüllülük suçlu bir kişiden çok farklı.
Guilty person is the person who is under duress,
Suçlu kişi, baskı altında olan kişidir.
under pressure, but a humble person is a free person.
baskı altında, ama mütevazı bir insan özgür bir insandır.
He is humble in his own freedom, in his own exuberance.
Kendi özgürlüğü içinde, kendi coşkusu içinde mütevazı.
Like the trees, when they are loaded with fruit
Ağaçlar gibi meyvelerle dolu olduklarında
they just bow to the Mother Earth.
sadece Toprak Ana'ya boyun eğiyorlar.
Like, if you go to the sea,
Mesela denize gidersen,
you'll find that all the trees around the sea,
denizin etrafındaki tüm ağaçları göreceksiniz.
specially the coconut trees,
özellikle hindistancevizi ağaçları,
all bend towards the sea
hepsi denize doğru viraj
because the sea has given them that speciality.
Çünkü deniz onlara bu uzmanlığı verdi.
The water that is in the coconut comes from the sea.
Hindistan cevizindeki su denizden geliyor.
So all of them have that respect,
Yani hepsinde bu saygı var.
that humility towards the sea.
denize karşı alçakgönüllülük.
In the same way a person who is not guilty
Aynı şekilde suçlu olmayan bir kişi
only will be really humble,
sadece gerçekten mütevazi olacak
because guilty people, as I told you,
çünkü dediğim gibi, suçlu insanlar
are aggressive by their sarcasm, by their nasty words,
iğnelemeleri, iğrenç sözleriyle saldırgan,
by their answering back, by their explanations.
cevaplarını vererek, açıklamalarıyla.
But a humble person is a free person,
Ama mütevazi bir insan özgür bir insandır.
free to be humble,
mütevazi olmakta özgür
free to be kindly,
nazik olmakta özgür
to be gentle, to be compassionate.
nazik olmak, şefkatli olmak.
And that sort of Sahaja yogis you have to be,
Ve bu tür bir Sahaja Yogi olmak zorundasın.
so that when people meet you
Böylece insanlar seninle tanıştığında
they're impressed by your humility.
alçakgönüllülüğünden etkilendiler.
But humility doesn't have any subservience
Ancak alçakgönüllülüğün hiçbir önemi yoktur.
- innocence and humility.
- masumiyet ve alçakgönüllülük.
I, I lack that quality completely.
Ben, bu kaliteden tamamen mahrumum.
I cannot be humble,
Mütevazi olamam,
and you should never try to humble Me down
ve beni asla alçakgönüllü olmaya çalışmamalısın
because that is not to be done.
çünkü bu yapılmayacak.
But nobody can say in My behavior when they meet Me
Ama kimse Benimle karşılaştığında davranışımda söyleyemez
that I'm not humble.
alçakgönüllü değilim.
I act as a very humble person.
Çok mütevazi biri olarak davranıyorum.
I can act as a very humble person but to be very frank,
Çok mütevazi bir insan olarak hareket edebilirim ama çok dürüst olmak gerekirse,
I have no humility of any kind within Me, no humility.
I have no humility of any kind within Me, no humility.
Compassion is very different from humility.
Compassion is very different from humility.
Humility is a human quality,
Humility is a human quality,
is a special quality only the bhaktas have.
is a special quality only the bhaktas have.
Only the bhaktas have, it's such a beautiful quality
Only the bhaktas have, it's such a beautiful quality
of taking the showers of bliss.
of taking the showers of bliss.
The one who gives bliss cannot be humble
The one who gives bliss cannot be humble
because it cannot take anything.
because it cannot take anything.
It's the only human beings who are humble,
It's the only human beings who are humble,
and who can take it and achieve it and receive it.
and who can take it and achieve it and receive it.
And the person who cannot take is so lonely, so lonely.
And the person who cannot take is so lonely, so lonely.
Such a person cannot get companionship with anyone,
Such a person cannot get companionship with anyone,
because it has to give, and give, and give.
because it has to give, and give, and give.
It's so lonely, and has to face everything oneself.
It's so lonely, and has to face everything oneself.
Those who are humble can only become friendly
Those who are humble can only become friendly
with each other, can share their problems with each other.
with each other, can share their problems with each other.
I cannot, because you have no solutions.
I cannot, because you have no solutions.
I have to solve My own problem.
I have to solve My own problem.
So the humility can only help you to articulate
So the humility can only help you to articulate
and to have rapport with your friends,
and to have rapport with your friends,
everyone, share your difficulties.
everyone, share your difficulties.
But again I have to warn you because it always happens,
But again I have to warn you because it always happens,
your humility should not be sympathetic.
your humility should not be sympathetic.
Humility is a detached person,
Humility is a detached person,
it's a detached quality.
it's a detached quality.
It's not a quality that gets attached
It's not a quality that gets attached
to one person or second person.
to one person or second person.
It's a humble style of life
It's a humble style of life
where you are not arrogant unnecessarily,
where you are not arrogant unnecessarily,
you don't shout at people.
you don't shout at people.
But in India we say the cow
But in India we say the cow
is a very humble animal.
is a very humble animal.
It gives its milk,
It gives its milk,
it provides everything,
it provides everything,
it doesn't attack anyone.
it doesn't attack anyone.
So humility is such a guard for you.
So humility is such a guard for you.
Of course, sometimes people take advantage of humble people,
Of course, sometimes people take advantage of humble people,
doesn't matter.
doesn't matter.
As long as you have not lost your humility,
As long as you have not lost your humility,
everything is all right.
everything is all right.
But people lose their humility.
But people lose their humility.
When people try to trouble them
When people try to trouble them
they become left-Vishuddhites
they become left-Vishuddhites
and then they lose their humility,
and then they lose their humility,
and that's one thing one should not lose;
and that's one thing one should not lose;
because if you have to keep connection with the Divine
because if you have to keep connection with the Divine
then you have to be humble.
then you have to be humble.
There's no other way.
Başka yol yok.
If you are not a humble person
If you are not a humble person
you cannot keep the relationship.
you cannot keep the relationship.
See, two qualities, like a plug and the socket.
See, two qualities, like a plug and the socket.
The plug has to be the plug,
The plug has to be the plug,
the socket has to be socket.
the socket has to be socket.
In the same way if you have to
In the same way if you have to
get something out of the Divine,
get something out of the Divine,
you have to be humble people.
you have to be humble people.
Through arrogance you will not get anything,
Through arrogance you will not get anything,
through aggression you'll not get anything,
through aggression you'll not get anything,
through anything .&amp; Some people also feel that
through anything .& Some people also feel that
"I love Mother," but that love is to be expressed
"I love Mother," but that love is to be expressed
through complete humility.
through complete humility.
That's the only way,
That's the only way,
that's the only channel through which you can approach Me,
that's the only channel through which you can approach Me,
there's no way out.
there's no way out.
So we end up today on a very high stage.
So we end up today on a very high stage.
It's the beginning of God's realization.
It's the beginning of God's realization.
But you must speed up with Me.
But you must speed up with Me.
It's not easy to keep speed with Me,
It's not easy to keep speed with Me,
so you have to speed up with Me.
so you have to speed up with Me.
If you have to go towards God's realization,
If you have to go towards God's realization,
first establish your sense of chastity and humility.
first establish your sense of chastity and humility.
May God bless you.
May God bless you.
So now, we start our Puja.
So now, we start our Puja.
You can wash My Feet if you want.
You can wash My Feet if you want.
The Ganesh Puja has to be there; one Ganesh stotra.
The Ganesh Puja has to be there; one Ganesh stotra.
Now for this you have to judge yourself.
Now for this you have to judge yourself.
I mean, you have to judge yourself not to accept guilt,
I mean, you have to judge yourself not to accept guilt,
but to judge yourself,
but to judge yourself,
"Am I a very forward type of a person,
"Am I a very forward type of a person,
do I go forward all the time?
do I go forward all the time?
Do I sit all the time before everybody else?
Do I sit all the time before everybody else?
Do I try to be arrogant to Mother?
Do I try to be arrogant to Mother?
Do I say "no" to Mother?
Do I say "no" to Mother?
Do I behave like?"
Do I behave like?"
And see all these points within yourself.
And see all these points within yourself.
It's not for others, it's for you to see,
It's not for others, it's for you to see,
"How far I go?
"How far I go?
Am I presumptuous, am I bumptious?
Am I presumptuous, am I bumptious?
Am I do things which I should not have done?"
Am I do things which I should not have done?"
Like that you go on into this thing.
Like that you go on into this thing.
These are symptomatic,
These are symptomatic,
symptoms coming from inside,
symptoms coming from inside,
and once you understand your symptoms,
and once you understand your symptoms,
"Oh, I am that.
"Oh, I am that.
All right, no more." Face it, tell yourself.
All right, no more." Face it, tell yourself.
As soon as you say, "I'm not guilty,"
As soon as you say, "I'm not guilty,"
it doesn't mean that you do not face it - you face it.
it doesn't mean that you do not face it - you face it.
All right. We'll have the washing of the Feet.
Tamam. We'll have the washing of the Feet.
Today I'm sorry, only the virgins can worship Me,
Today I'm sorry, only the virgins can worship Me,
only the real virgins can worship Me - little girls,
only the real virgins can worship Me - little girls,
if there are any.
if there are any.
Hallo, there are, they are coming.
Hallo, there are, they are coming.
Come along, come along, come along, all the children.
Come along, come along, come along, all the children.
Hallo, come up
Hallo, come up
Nice frock!
Nice frock!
Ah, ha! Ah, ha!
Ah, ha! Ah, ha!
Oh, very nice dress, Athena!
Oh, very nice dress, Athena!
Come, hah! Now, where are the others?
Come, hah! Now, where are the others?
Come along, all the children, all the children.
Come along, all the children, all the children.
Only the children can do that.
Only the children can do that.
All right, sit down, sit down. Come forward.
All right, sit down, sit down. Come forward.
Oh, somebody's wearing a sari!
Oh, somebody's wearing a sari!
All the children.
All the children.
Sit down, sit down, sit down.
Sit down, sit down, sit down.
All the children have to sit down here, all right?
All the children have to sit down here, all right?
Hallo, India, how are you?
Hallo, India, how are you?
Be careful of this light, all right?
Be careful of this light, all right?
Can you, can you put that to one side a little bit,
Can you, can you put that to one side a little bit,
for the children I'm rather worried,
for the children I'm rather worried,
and then we can enlighten it.
and then we can enlighten it.
Ah, thank you.
Ah, thank you.
More are coming, they are in the coming.
More are coming, they are in the coming.
In future we are going to have lots of them,
In future we are going to have lots of them,
and maybe you will all have to sit outside.
and maybe you will all have to sit outside.
Now they sit outside;
Now they sit outside;
after some time you all will have to sit outside!
after some time you all will have to sit outside!
That would be the best!
That would be the best!
They'll all say, "Out, out!"
They'll all say, "Out, out!"
Let them grow!
Let them grow!
A new army's coming forward.
A new army's coming forward.
I think you get...can do that.
I think you get...can do that.
You give it to him, he'll do it, he'll just, he'll do it.
You give it to him, he'll do it, he'll just, he'll do it.
He'll do it carefully now.
He'll do it carefully now.
Come along, come along.
Come along, come along.
Gavin, you move that both sides just a little bit.
Gavin, you move that both sides just a little bit.
Hallo, come along, this side.
Hallo, come along, this side.
Now all the little ones should come forward first,
Now all the little ones should come forward first,
all the little ones here.
all the little ones here.
One - all of you are little ones, all right?
One - all of you are little ones, all right?
Now, who are the littlest?
Now, who are the littlest?
Now, is there anyone else coming up?
Now, is there anyone else coming up?
Sit down, sit down, sit down, sit down.
Sit down, sit down, sit down, sit down.
All right, you come here, you want to come here?
All right, you come here, you want to come here?
All right, now, give him a chance there, all right?
All right, now, give him a chance there, all right?
Now let it be. Now bring him here.
Now let it be. Now bring him here.
Now, all the girls should come first,
Now, all the girls should come first,
and all the boys later.
and all the boys later.
Should we do that way,
Should we do that way,
or should we have the little boys first?
or should we have the little boys first?
Little boys is better, isn't it - you are sisters,
Little boys is better, isn't it - you are sisters,
after all.
after all.
Now let's have the little boys first, all right.
Now let's have the little boys first, all right.
All the little boys, and then the sisters will do that.
All the little boys, and then the sisters will do that.
Now who are the little boys?
Now who are the little boys?
Ah, all of them.
Ah, all of them.
Now the sisters have to wait for a while, all right?
Now the sisters have to wait for a while, all right?
See, see the thing, see;
See, see the thing, see;
how easily acceptable this is.
how easily acceptable this is.
All the sisters - now she's a sister - now come along,
All the sisters - now she's a sister - now come along,
all the sisters have to go back.
all the sisters have to go back.
Did she follow?
Did she follow?
All right, you stand there.
All right, you stand there.
All right, tell her.
All right, tell her.
You stand there. You come forward.
You stand there. You come forward.
All right. Now all the boys, come along.
Tamam. Now all the boys, come along.
You come here.
You come here.
All the boys have to do it, all the sisters have to wait.
All the boys have to do it, all the sisters have to wait.
There's the - there are no boys there, no more?
There's the - there are no boys there, no more?
Come, come, come, come, come; come!
Come, come, come, come, come; come!
All right. Now, everyone.
Tamam. Now, everyone.
If Pat's son is there you can call him, Pat's son, all right.
If Pat's son is there you can call him, Pat's son, all right.
He will do it.
He will do it.
Everyone else should sit down. Ah, good.
Everyone else should sit down. Ah, good.
Now all the sisters, all the sisters are sitting down first.
Now all the sisters, all the sisters are sitting down first.
You see, the boys are doing first, all right?
You see, the boys are doing first, all right?
All the sisters are standing there to look after the boys.
All the sisters are standing there to look after the boys.
Come along.
Come along.
The boys have to come here.
The boys have to come here.
Come, come, come; come, come.
Come, come, come; come, come.
All right, let him sit down, he's the boy.
All right, let him sit down, he's the boy.
Come along, sit down, you are the boy!
Come along, sit down, you are the boy!
Hah! You're a boy?
Hah! You're a boy?
Those who are boys must sit down.
Those who are boys must sit down.
When you sit down, he'll sit down for a while,
When you sit down, he'll sit down for a while,
he'll sit down. He's a nice boy. Not to be shy;
he'll sit down. He's a nice boy. Not to be shy;
nobody has to be shy in here, all right?
nobody has to be shy in here, all right?
Hah! Now come along, all the boys,
Hah! Now come along, all the boys,
those who are shy are not boys!
those who are shy are not boys!
No, he's a boy, he's good. All right.
No, he's a boy, he's good. Tamam.
If you are boys, you should not be shy.
If you are boys, you should not be shy.
Only the girls are shy.
Only the girls are shy.
He's shy. It's all right, don't force,
He's shy. It's all right, don't force,
it's all right, don't force the children.
it's all right, don't force the children.
Ross is here?
Ross is here?
He's not here?
He's not here?
Come along.
Come along.
Now you look after that side.
Now you look after that side.
Give him, so that he'll do it.
Give him, so that he'll do it.
You have to wash My Feet.
You have to wash My Feet.
All right, come along. Say the mantra of
All right, come along. Say the mantra of
just say it...Into your hands.
just say it...Into your hands.
Please leave it to him,
Please leave it to him,
and you have to wash My Feet, all right?
and you have to wash My Feet, all right?
Now, be careful with that.
Now, be careful with that.
You see, that's why I have called you,
You see, that's why I have called you,
because they are small children.
because they are small children.
Now, wash My Feet.
Now, wash My Feet.
Tell them how to wash.
Tell them how to wash.
Now, one by one, come along.
Now, one by one, come along.
Wash My Feet.
Wash My Feet.
Yes, Markandeya, you wash it, all right.
Yes, Markandeya, you wash it, all right.
Come along, all of you, wash it.
Come along, all of you, wash it.
Wash it, wash it hard.
Wash it, wash it hard.
All right, we'll, we'll have a second group, all right?
All right, we'll, we'll have a second group, all right?
And next we'll have second group also.
And next we'll have second group also.
That's good. You rub it. Rub it, rub it now.
That's good. You rub it. Rub it, rub it now.
Rub it.This one also.
Rub it.This one also.
Come along, wash My Feet.
Come along, wash My Feet.
Dennis, let them, wash My Feet.
Dennis, let them, wash My Feet.
Come, wash, wash. Wash, wash, wash.
Come, wash, wash. Wash, wash, wash.
Now come along - hallo! Come, wash My Feet.
Now come along - hallo! Come, wash My Feet.
Wash My Feet.
Wash My Feet.
Good. Good. Now
İyi. İyi. şimdi
Now the other boys should do it,
Now the other boys should do it,
all right? You've done it?
all right? You've done it?
All right, now the other boys should wash now.
All right, now the other boys should wash now.
You've done it, Hanu? Washed it?
You've done it, Hanu? Washed it?
All right.
Tamam.
The bigger boys. You come along.
The bigger boys. You come along.
Let them wash, all right?
Let them wash, all right?
Nanaka? Now let them wash, all right?
Nanaka? Now let them wash, all right?
Now you get up. You get up now?
Now you get up. You get up now?
Markandeya? Let them come. All right?
Markandeya? Let them come. Tamam?
Ah, that's good. You also Hanu?
Ah, that's good. You also Hanu?
Let them come. All right? Come forward
Let them come. Tamam? Come forward
Now, come along. Done, all right?
Now, come along. Done, all right?
Now let the girls come in.
Now let the girls come in.
Now the girls come in.
Now the girls come in.
Let the boys go, boys have to go.
Let the boys go, boys have to go.
You didn't do it?
You didn't do it?
All right, ask him to do.
All right, ask him to do.
You come along, wash it.
You come along, wash it.
Now, all of you should get up and let the girls do it.
Now, all of you should get up and let the girls do it.
All right, you all get up now? Boys have to wash.
All right, you all get up now? Boys have to wash.
I think he has washed.
I think he has washed.
You washed it? No? All right, come along, come along.
You washed it? Yok hayır? All right, come along, come along.
Put the water here.
Put the water here.
Let him come.
Let him come.
All right, come forward. Let him come.
All right, come forward. Let him come.
Good. Get up, Nanak, get up.
İyi. Get up, Nanak, get up.
Danya?
Danya?
Just a minute, just a minute.
Just a minute, just a minute.
Some of you - I'll call all of you one by one, all right?
Some of you - I'll call all of you one by one, all right?
Now, wash it. Wash it now, wash it now.
Now, wash it. Wash it now, wash it now.
Just help here
Just help here
Done! Now, now, let the others come in, now.
Done! Now, now, let the others come in, now.
Get up now. Girls have to come in now.
Get up now. Girls have to come in now.
All the boys have to go.
All the boys have to go.
Nanaka, you get up now, get up, get up nicely.
Nanaka, you get up now, get up, get up nicely.
Let the girls come in.
Let the girls come in.
Now, come on.
Now, come on.
Where is Olympia?
Where is Olympia?
You stay here. You stay here. Stay here.
You stay here. You stay here. Burada kal.
Girls have to stay.
Girls have to stay.
Boys can go.
Boys can go.
They have to go now, because this is the girls'puja.
They have to go now, because this is the girls'puja.
Both the hands.
Both the hands.
All right? Now wipe your hands.
Tamam? Now wipe your hands.
All right, put it on your head.
All right, put it on your head.
All the girls have to sit here.
All the girls have to sit here.
Olympia, where is she? She's coming.
Olympia, where is she? She's coming.
Sit down, sit down, sit down, sit down.
Sit down, sit down, sit down, sit down.
All right.
Tamam.
Olympia, come.
Olympia, come.
All the girls. You washed, have you?
All the girls. You washed, have you?
You've washed, all right.
You've washed, all right.
Take out this one, let's take out this one.
Take out this one, let's take out this one.
Now take the names,
Now take the names,
hundred-and-eight names straightforward,
hundred-and-eight names straightforward,
because that's really the Gauri's names.
because that's really the Gauri's names.
Hard.
Hard.
Rub it hard. All right.
Rub it hard. Tamam.
No, no. You must take My name, Gavin,
Hayır hayır. You must take My name, Gavin,
otherwise vibrations don't flow.
otherwise vibrations don't flow.
You have to say full thing - what can I do,
You have to say full thing - what can I do,
because there's the limit.
because there's the limit.
You want to do it?
You want to do it?
You can come. Be careful, all right?
You can come. Be careful, all right?
Because everything comes in the photograph.
Because everything comes in the photograph.
Now just a minute, just a minute.
Now just a minute, just a minute.
I'll ask everybody to help.
I'll ask everybody to help.
Now don't fight.
Now don't fight.
Everybody will be doing it.
Everybody will be doing it.
Girls will go away. Just put it here.
Girls will go away. Just put it here.
Thank you very much. It's all right,
Thank you very much. It's all right,
rub your hands like this.
rub your hands like this.
All hands become red.
All hands become red.
All over.
All over.
Rub it like this all over, all the fingers.
Rub it like this all over, all the fingers.
Do it with your heart,
Do it with your heart,
because what is happening is that it's all mental.
because what is happening is that it's all mental.
Do it with your heart.
Do it with your heart.
You, what you are saying is saying to Me;
You, what you are saying is saying to Me;
I'm sitting before you - fortunate people!
I'm sitting before you - fortunate people!
Do it with heart, then only it will be - open your heart,
Do it with heart, then only it will be - open your heart,
and do it with your heart.
and do it with your heart.
Come along!
Come along!
Without feeling guilty, that's very important.
Without feeling guilty, that's very important.
Sari of Vishnumaya is very beautiful.
Sari of Vishnumaya is very beautiful.
Showing the two tipes of flowers and the lights in between.
Showing the two tipes of flowers and the lights in between.
This is French.
This is French.
Big significance.
Big significance.
French sari for Vishnumaya.
French sari for Vishnumaya.
Just say "Vishnumaya" - that's all.
Just say "Vishnumaya" - that's all.
Today is not Shiva's Puja,
Today is not Shiva's Puja,
and without His Puja how can you take His name?
and without His Puja how can you take His name?
Just say Vishnumaya: "Twameva Sakshat Shri Vishnumaya..."
Just say Vishnumaya: "Twameva Sakshat Shri Vishnumaya..."
May God bless you all.
May God bless you all.
With Shiva's name both My Feet
With Shiva's name both My Feet
have become absolutely frozen. All right.
have become absolutely frozen. Tamam.
All right. Bow down.
Tamam. Bow down.
May God bless you all.
May God bless you all.